# Matt Higgins

Fullstack Web Developer - Denver, CO 415-686-6218 – mhiggins.louis@gmail.com

<u>Linkedin</u>(https://www.linkedin.com/in/mhiggie/) - <u>Github</u>(https://github.com/matthewhiggins415) - <u>Portfolio(https://matthewhiggins415.github.io/mattsPortfolio/)</u>

Adaptive, innovative, web developer with 2 years of experience working with teams to manage professional full stack projects. I am a clear communicator that asks questions when stuck and is always open to improvement.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Node, EJS, DTL | Databases - PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Libraries and Frameworks - React (class based and hooks), Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api, CRUD api, web API, styled-components (React), Stripe api, Agile SCRUM team focused.

#### **PROJECTS**

easyRent Jan 2022

(jQuery, Stripe Connected Accounts, MongoDB, Node JS, mongoose, express, passport, bcrypt, javascript, html, css)

- Fullstack project enabling landlords to CRUD properties, tenants, upkeep tasks, and payments.
- Implemented, tested, and delivered high quality scalable solutions.
- Integrates Stripe Connected Accounts so landlords can automatically collect payments from tenants

Kakeibo Budgeting March 2022

(React, styled-components, framer-motion, MongoDB, Mongoose, ApexCharts, Express, bcrypt, javascript, css)

- Fullstack ecommerce SPA. CRUD API for enabling users to manage personal expenses using Japanese budgeting philosophy of Kakeibo.
- Uses ApexCharts to visualize data of users total expenses.
- Turned wireframes and user stories into effective, stable features.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Marketing & Sales Lead Jan 2020 - Dec 2021

Juni Learning | San Francisco, CA | Remote

- Built wireframes for devOps team to streamline user onboarding and increase conversion.
- Measured online marketing performance and increased lead conversion by 60% within three months.
- Brought together marketing, engineering, and operations teams to optimize web design based on self-sourced customer feedback. Reduced lead drop off by nearly 40%.

Account Executive Sales March 2017 - June 2019

Reflektive | San Francisco, CA

- Managed full cycle deal from source to close average size 45K. Attained quota of 130%.
- Led 20 person sales team with most deals closed in a year. Optimized deal cycles to be as efficient as possible.
- Trained incoming sales reps and colleagues on how to optimize their deal cycles.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Software Engineering Immersive Program**

August 2021 - March 2022

General Assembly | Remote

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 8 month, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

# Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) in Political Science

2012 - 2016

University of Colorado | Boulder, CO

Awards: Accepted into prestigious CatalyzeCU program, an incubator for student-led businesses. Collaborated with business partners to deliver and present a full business plan to 200+ potential investors.